

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - IOT\DEVOPS

Curitiba, Paraná, Brazil

🛘 (+55) 41-992227969 | 🗷 valdeci@outlook.my | 🏶 coderade.github.io | 🖸 coderade | 🖹 coderade | 🛅 valdeci | 🕲 coderade

"It is hard to fail, but it is worse never to have tried to succeed."

Summary.

Software developer focused on open-source technologies, I am currently working with IOT/DevOps development at Rumo company.

Software developer with 5 years of experience, I was able to work mainly with large projects using GIS (Geographic Information System) and IOT (Internet of Things) technologies, DevOps (Deploys automation, configuration management, and so on), as well as websystems and websites for large clients in Brazil and the World.

In addition to experience in large proprietary projects, I have good experience in open-source projects always focused on following the main standards of code, quality, testability and safety.

Arch Linux User, Java Certified, I have an experience focused on Back-end/DevOps development, but I have a good knowledge of AWS stack technologies (DynamoDB, IOT, Lambda, EC2, SNS, SQS, Kinesis, among others) and technologies like Python, Ruby on Rails, JS, Node.js, PHP, Drupal, Java, React e React-Native, AngularJS e IONIC, Adobe AEM, ExtJS, PostgreSQL, MySQL and others.

Work Experience ____

Rumo Curitiba, Brazil

IOT\DevOps Developer

Oct. 2017 - PRESENT

- Responsible for the development of real-time communication systems between equipment used by the Rumo company's trains and Internet (IOT) for data processing such as BI, monotoring and alarms, Machine and Learning and etc.
- In this opportunity I worked using the maximum of AWS Stack (EC2, DynamoDB, IOT, S3, Lambda, MQTT, SQS, SNS, Kinesis) for data processing and Hadoop, Cloudera, Impala, Hive (OAC). In addition to leveraging open-source technologies such as Python, Node. Js, Javascript (ES6), Java, Angular JS and others.
- The initial focus of the project was the initiation or improvement of the equipment used in the route by the company's RUMO trains running an average of 3 million rules in AWS for sending data to systems such as PRTG (monitoring) and Oracle Analytics Cloud (BigData).
- In addition to IOT and Big Data projects, I had the opportunity to participate in the implementation of the DevOps methodology in Rumo with the automation of deploys of SOA, OSB, Web projects, automation of the update of the cards in Jira. In addition to the implementation and deployment of migration from SVN Version Control to GIT (Bitbucket) and documentation with Confluence of projects.
- In the Rumo technology area we use the best of agile methodologies using Scrum and Kanban and tools like Bitbucket (GIT) for project and code version management (VCS) and Jira and Confluence for documentation and issues.

Mirum Agency Curitiba, Brazil

Systems Analyst & Developer

Apr. 2016 - Oct. 2017

- Development and maintenance of Mobile and Web applications using JS, IONIC, AngularJS, Cordova, Node.js, Adobe AEM, PHP, Codelgniter, Drupal, MySQL and other technologies.
- In this opportunity I worked developing web apps for big clients on the work like the Activia Danone websites, The West Ham United team website and Ebook App for the Learning Factory company
- In the IT area of Mirum we used agile methodologies using Scrum and Kanban and tools like Bitbucket, Gitlab, Github (GIT) for project and code version management (VCS) and Jira and Confluence for documentation and issues.

Veltec Londrina, Brazil

WEB/GIS DEVELOPER

Jul. 2015 - Mar. 2016

- Responsible for the development and maintenance of web applications used by the company's customers. I worked as a Full Stack developer using the technologies Ruby on Rails, Node.js, PostgreSQL, ExtJS, Python, ShellScript, Georeferencing, Java, AngularJS and etc.
- My main goal in the company was to be responsible for migrating the company's Georeferencing System (first development in Delphi and .shp files) to Web technology taking full advantage of open source technologies like Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, Postgis, Python, OpenStreetMap, Java, Shellscript, AngularJs, EXTJS, D3.js, OpenLayers, Leaflet among others.
- In the area of technology of Veltec we used agile methodologies using Scrum (daily meeting, Pair Progamming, Code Review and etc) and Kanban and tools like Bitbucket (GIT) for project and code version management (VCS) and Redmine and Confluence for documentation and issues.

Z3 WEB Digital Agency

Londrina, Brazil

WEB DEVELOPER

Jan. 2015 - Jul. 2016

- Development and maintenance of websites using technologies such as Html5, PHP, Css, CakePHP, Javascript, Wordpress, Jquery, MySQL, among others.
- In the Z3 Web technology area we used tools like Bitbucket (Git) for project and code version management (VCS) and RunRunIt for task management.

Amcor Cambé, Brazil

IT SUPPORT INTERNSHIP PROGRAM

- · Technical support for Windows and Linux systems, Lotus Notes and ERP System Progress, backup systems and etc.
- Support for the Head Office in Brazil and offices in São Paulo.

Certifications

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer

Curitiba, Brazil

Jan. 2013 - Feb. 2013

ORACL F

May. 2014

· A Java SE 7 Oracle Certified Associate (OCA) has built a foundational understanding of Java, while acquiring knowledge of general programming.

Expert User Londrina, Brazil

RUNRUN.IT May. 2013

• A RunRun.it Expert User has an awesome knowledge about the RunRun.it system.

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

Finalist (14th / 100), The Big Hackathon Campus Party 2017 2017

São Paulo, Brazil

Languages

English Advanced Portuguese Native Spanish Elementary French Elementary

Projects

Open Source Projects

Github

Rumo

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/CODERADE

Jan. 2014 - PRESENT

· Source of my open-source projects.

Rumo DevOps SOA/OSB/WEB | SVN to Git migration

PROPRIETARY SOFTWARE

Aug. 2018 - PRESENT

- In this project I had the opportunity to participate in the implementation of the DevOps methodology in Rumo with the automation of deploys of SOA, OSB, Web projects, automation of the update of the cards in Jira.
- In addition I had the opportunity to work in the changes of configuration management in the RUMO IT area as the implementation and deployment of migration from SVN Version Control to GIT (Bitbucket) and documentation of projects with Confluence.

Supervisory system Rumo

Sep. 2017 - PRESENT PROPRIETARY SOFTWARE · Software Project with the goal of implementing and improving real-time communication systems between equipment used by the locomotives

- concessioned by Rumo and Internet of thing (IOT) for handling data such as BI, monitoring, Machine Learning and etc. • The initial focus of the project was the initiation or improvement of the equipment used in the route by the company's RUMO trains running an
- average of 3 million rules in AWS for sending data to systems such as PRTG (monitoring) and Oracle Analytics Cloud (BigData). • This project was developed using the maximum of AWS Stack (EC2, DynamoDB, IOT, S3, Lambda, MQTT, SQS, SNS, Kinesis) for data processing and Hadoop, Cloudera, Impala, Hive (OAC). In addition to leveraging open-source technologies such as Python, Node. Js, Javascript (ES6), Java, AngularJS and others.

Activia Websites Mirum Agency

Development and maintenance of Activia Danone's global websites.

Nov. 2016 - Jan. 2017

- The sites were developed using the technologies Drupal, MySQL, JS, Node.js and others.

Tim Live Website / System

HTTPS://WWW.ACTIVIA.US.COM

HTTP://WWW.LIVETIM.COM.BR

Mirum Agency

Apr. 2016 - Sep. 2016

• Responsible for the website and the backend development of the Live TIM website - the TIM Broadband Internet of Fiber Optics in Brazil.

· Website/ System developed using the technologies PHP, CodeIgniter, MySQL, Jquery, Mustache, Sass and etc.

West Ham United F.C. Website

Mirum Agency

Apr. 2016 - Sep. 2016

HTTP://WWW.WHUFC.COM

- Backend Development of the website of the English Soccer Club West Ham United.
- Technologies used: Drupal 8, PHP, JS, MySQL, Sass, Node.js, Bootstrap and others.

VALDECI GOMES · RÉSUMÉ OCTOBER 23, 2018

Veltec MapSrv System Veltec

HTTP://VELTEC3G.COM.BR Jul. 2015 - Feb. 2016

• Web system based on OpenStreetMap stack for creating and processing maps for systems used by customers of the company Veltec S.A. This system consists of several modules taking advantage of proprietary and open source projects and thus enabling the editing and rendering maps as well other features such as geocoding a proprietary way by the company.

• In the system development was taken advantage of the best open source technologies, thus being used PHP, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, Ruby On Rails, Node.js, Python, Linux, among others technologies.

Education

PUC (Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Paraná)

Londrina, Brazil

ESPECIALIZATION IN APP DEVELOPMENT

Jan. 2016 - Mar. 2018

The Majoring Diploma in App Development offers an advanced curriculum in the development of solutions for mobile devices, interrelating
methodologies and market technologies.

UNOPAR (Universidade Norte do Paraná)

Londrina, Brazil

TECHNOLOGIST DEGREE IN SYSTEM ANALYSIS AND DEVELOPMENT

Jan. 2013 - Dec. 2015

- This course I had the opportunity to study with a scholarship.
- Basic training area of this course aims to integrate the student in the computer field, from the perspective of its object and give the theoretical and practical reasoning for that he can interpret and follow the disciplines of professional area, pointing for relations of Information Technology with the other disciplines.

Instituto Senai Londrina, Brazil

TECHNICAL COURSE, SYSTEMS PROGRAMMING

Jan. 2014 - Mar. 2015

- This course I had the opportunity to study with a scholarship.
- Course will form a professional who will apply the database concepts and use the key technologies related to DELPHI and Java platform for developing systems

Extracurricular Activity

Volunteer Computer Teacher

Londrina, Brazil

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Feb. 2015 - Sep. 2015

• The CVL, through volunteers, created the Employability Project, whose goal is to empower and guide professionally, people without socioe-conomic conditions for (re) integration to the labor market, working on personal and professional development of these people (Knowledge, Skills, attitudes and Values), and encourage reflection, critical thinking, argumentation, criticality, observation, decision-making, exchange of experiences, teamwork, new technical knowledge, technology and innovation, as well the motivation to start and / or return to regular studies. In this project I act teaching computer classes as a volunteer teacher in PLDA (Patronato Penitentiary of Londrina), aimed at inclusion and citizenship, giving opportunity to the labor market and social life for egresses of the criminal justice system and also people who can't pay for a course.

For more details, please take a look on my LinkedIn profile.